[ Watch on kissFlix.co ]
[Spring of The Blade]
[Episode 14]
Where is the money?
I asked you, where is the money?
Money?
There's no more money.
-Are you all right, Lord Wei?
-Lord Wei.
What a brilliant scheme, My Lord.
This move is very exquisite.
On one hand, you quelled the disaster.
On the other hand,
you forced the grain merchants
to lower their prices.
Lord Yan, you really
have Hengtang in the palm of your hand.
But I am a little worried
about Your Lordship.
The situation in the future
will probably be difficult to control.
I haven't thought about that.
No matter what the situation is
in the future,
I must thank Lord Xie.
If not for your secret help,
I couldn't have pulled this off.
I will definitely go
to the capital in the future
and put in a few good words for you.
Thank you.
Lord Xie,
aren't you going with me to see
how grandly the disaster relief is going?
Lord Yan,
as you can see,
Shu
has family matters to deal with,
so he asked for a day off.
You'd better go back first.
Qingyuan,
see the guest out.
Yes.
♪ I counted every moment ♪
♪ Memories take roots;
the annual rings grow ♪
♪ Who bore the parting wind ♪
♪ And wove it gently into the warmth
of the past? ♪
♪ I honor every scar upon your hand ♪
Your Lordship,
Everyone says you are a corrupt official,
♪ Through endless nights,
a lone soul wanders this mortal world ♪
but I never expected
that today you would
save countless starving people
in Hengtang,
♪ Turning back, we embrace—
one fleeting moment of love and hate ♪
and save me as well.
I genuinely admire Your Lordship.
From now on, wherever Your Lordship goes
to listen to music,
♪ As flowers fall beneath the dusk ♪
drink with courtesans, or spend money,
♪ Sorrowed by many a farewell,
comforted by sweet memories ♪
if you're willing,
-I—
-What?
♪ One life, one love,
one heart devoted to you ♪
What did you say I'd spend money on?
♪ In the depths of darkness,
you are the stars ♪
♪ Trample the abyss, together we run ♪
Thank you for saving me today,
Your Lordship.
♪ May we grow deep in years together,
sharing one life and one pillow ♪
♪ Rise and fall as one,
whether we're united or apart ♪
♪ Hand in hand,
we brave all the storms of life ♪
♪ Never to part, forevermore ♪
It's not safe in Hengtang tonight.
If I'm not around,
you must protect yourself.
Bad news, Master!
Master, bad news!
Chuntai...
stopped breathing.
Master...
I gave birth to two sons
for the Xie family,
and I raised Zhenglun so well.
Yet you say I'm faking it.
Why couldn't Xie Qingyuan
be the one faking it?
-I didn't kill anyone.
-Mother, please get up.
You're bullying me!
Enough.
Things outside are annoying enough.
As for how your matter should be handled,
Master and Old Madam will decide.
Aren't you the Head Madam?
You can make the decision.
Yes.
Everyone, calm down.
Donglin.
What is Wei Changyan
up to?
I sent someone to investigate,
but there's no reply.
However,
I heard the east pier
is in chaos right now—
the grain merchants
are making a scene.
Listen to me.
Without my permission today,
no one is allowed to
step out of the residence.
Yes!
Calm down, everyone!
Calm down!
Please listen to me!
Lord Wei.
Our ships
have been docked here
for over half a month!
If you don't buy our grain now,
what are we supposed to do?
Exactly, what should we do?
What should we do?
How are we supposed to live?
The grain collection
was agreed to be today.
Why are you giving grain away instead?
A bunch of evil officials!
Liars!
-Liars!
That's a big claim!
You're speaking nonsense!
H-How dare you!
Insolent commoners!
Outrageous!
Bastards!
Outrageous, really.
Lord Wei,
where are you going?
Isn't it time to pay
the profit you promised me?
Sir,
you don't understand.
There must be
some misunderstanding here.
Go back and wait for me for a few days.
I will definitely give you
an explanation, okay?
We agreed on today,
so it must be today.
But...
the price difference
for these 1,800 dan of grain,
even if you kill me, I can't afford it.
Help!
Guards!
You guys go this way
and block the front door!
The rest, follow me this way!
Mother, what's going on?
I don't know.
With the city tower drums
beating like that,
if they weren't collecting grain
in the middle of the night,
I would have thought
they were crying out my grievances.
What's going on?
I have no idea.
Master!
Father!
Master...
Old Madam!
Nanny Liu.
What is going on?
It's complete chaos outside.
These northern bandits
have reached the outer city!
They specifically target wealthy families.
They say the northern bandits...
They kill any men they see,
and as for women, they...
What should we do?
Don't be afraid.
Mother is here.
Don't be afraid. It's okay.
Father and Mother are here.
Don't panic.
Stay calm!
Yuejian,
put out all unnecessary lights first
so we don't attract
the bandits' attention.
Yes.
Good thing you prepared in advance.
Trouble really arrived today.
I'm more curious about
how these northern bandits
managed to break through so smoothly
and reach the outer city.
Who cares how they broke in?
We must kill the bandits,
but all the more must Wei Changyan
be killed.
I've waited for 9 years,
and I don't want to wait anymore.
Where do you think that scumbag
could be hiding?
Lord Yan!
I don't care what my father thinks.
If he won't help you,
I will.
In the past, I only thought
you were a corrupt official.
Only today did I realize
you bore all that infamy
to protect the people of Hengtang.
I absolutely won't stand by
and do nothing.
We will protect the people with you.
Report!
The northern bandits have reached
the outside of the south gate!
Understood.
Pei Guanling,
notify all major city gates
to defend strictly.
Do not let a single bandit
slip through.
Yes, sir.
Soldiers!
Now,
the time has come to prove yourselves.
Please follow me to wipe out the bandits
and defend the people of Hengtang.
Kill them!
-Kill!
Mother,
I'm scared.
Don't be afraid,
your father is here.
Master, bad news!
Master!
Master, bad news.
Master...
-What are you panicking for?
-Master...
Speak slowly.
Master,
the northern bandits...
they have attacked the East Gate.
They are burning, killing,
and looting everywhere,
and will be here soon.
What should we do?
Mother!
What are you panicking for?
With the patriarch around,
what's there to panic for?
Nanny Liu,
keep an eye out.
If there is any situation,
report it immediately.
Yes, Madam.
Master...
Master,
why not ask the government office
to send troops to protect us?
It's chaos outside.
The government office has few soldiers.
They can hardly protect themselves.
Then...
Then what should we do?
The Marquis' residence—
they have soldiers.
First Madam,
aren't you close
with the Marchioness of Danyang?
How about...
I don't have that much influence.
However,
to ask of the Marquis' residence...
I'm afraid
only Fourth Lady can do it.
That's right.
Not only did they take a liking
to Qingyuan,
she also has a close relationship
with Lord Yan.
For her sake,
they probably wouldn't sit by
and do nothing.
Mother,
it's full of bandits outside.
Who knows where
Lord Yan and the heir is?
Yet you're asking
a weak lady like her to...
Who told you to speak? Sit down.
All right,
stop talking.
Right now,
even if we mobilize soldiers
from all the residences,
distant water can't put out a nearby fire.
The personal guards of the Xie Residence
have just left for the Northern Frontier.
It seems this is the only way.
Qingyuan.
See if...
you can risk
going to the Yan residence
to ask Lord Yan for reinforcements.
Kill!
Hurry!
I know
I shouldn't ask a weak lady like you
to risk your life for something like this.
But the Xie family...
Never mind.
Forget it.
Mother.
I am unfilial.
Last Lantern Festival,
I had a dream.
In the dream, a boy sang:
"All flowers fade during the full moon."
It seems this prophecy
is coming true today.
Alas, the century-old foundation
of our Xie family
is coming to an end.
Qingyuan.
If it weren't an emergency,
I wouldn't want you to take this risk.
I wish I could take your place.
But right now, only you
can save the Xie family.
Are you willing to go?
We can talk about other things
after we survive this disaster.
Mother.
It's too dangerous.
I will go.
My Lady.
Stay here.
Don't cause me trouble.
But I have one condition.
After the bandit rebellion is quelled,
my mother's case
must be thoroughly reinvestigated.
No one
is allowed to refuse.
All right.
As long as
you're willing to save the Xie Residence,
we'll agree to any request.
Old Madam.
Master?
I'll go with Fourth Sister.
Nonsense!
What are you going for?
Qingyuan.
For the sake of the family,
please make the trip.
Zhenglun,
take good care of your sister.
Yes.
If anything happens to her,
I won't forgive you!
Yes!
Qingyuan.
We're counting on you.
Be careful.
Close the city gates!
Stop the bandits from escaping!
After them!
Over here!
Here!
Quick!
Chase them!
Stop!
Don't run!
This way!
Thank you, Brother.
You are willing to take risks
to seek help for the Xie family—
a great act of righteousness.
But I always believe
that my mother
didn't kill anyone on her own will.
Please, Fourth Sister,
don't blame my mother.
Over here!
Go find Lord Yan.
What about you—
Go!
Go quickly!
Che!
I think I saw Wei Changyan.
Lord Yan!
There's a riot in the east of the city.
What about the Xie Residence?
The Xie Residence is fine.
I just heard...
Heard what?
They asked Fourth Lady
to seek help from Your Lordship.
Where is she?
Not sure yet.
The enemy is right in front of you,
and you're still thinking about
that woman?
Do you really think you're Yan Rui?
Che.
Wait for me to come back.
Brother!
Shen Run!
Your Lordship!
General!
I am Qingyuan, the fourth daughter
of the army inspector Xie family.
My family is in danger!
Please save them, Your Lordship!
My Lord!
No shouting!
Closing the city gates is to prevent
bandits from sneaking in.
Why?
Exactly! Why?
Your Lordship.
I am the fourth daughter of
the army inspector
Xie Residence of Hengtang.
My family is trapped.
Please save them, Your Lordship.
I didn't bring any money,
only this jade pendant.
Please do me a favor, Your Lordship.
We heed the imperial decree!
Fourth Lady.
Master Pei!
My eldest brother...
He's surrounded by bandits.
Go save him!
He's in the third alley
on the street behind us.
Follow me!
Fourth Lady.
This jade pendant,
where did it come from?
Lord Yan gave it to me.
Do you recognize it, Master Pei?
Put the jade pendant away quickly.
This is an imperially bestowed
pass.
From the Imperial Throne Room
down to the imperial guards,
anyone holding this token
will have all doors opened for them,
passing without hindrance.
If it weren't wartime,
I would have to speak to you on my knees.
Lord Yan
is really generous.
We'll form an alliance
and share weal and woe.
So you treat what I gave you
as a mere toy.
Anyway, it's all just stuff
that was forced on me by others.
I really don't think
I need that jade pendant.
Then listen carefully.
You will need it.
Master Pei,
take me to find Lord Yan.
Master Pei!
Lord Yan is in the west of the city,
surrounded by a large group of bandits.
What did you say?
What happened to Yan Rui?
When Master Shen's reinforcements arrived,
there were only dozens of corpses
on the ground.
There were no survivors.
Where is Yan Rui?
We're identifying the bodies.
Lord Yan's survival
is unknown.
But I heard there are no survivors
in the west of the city.
Lord Yan may have…
Shut up!
Find him now!
Yes!
♪ Spring comes to the long gate,
green grass sprouts ♪
It's not safe in Hengtang tonight.
If I'm not around,
you must protect yourself.
♪ Red plums bear dewdrops,
bright and serene ♪
♪ Year by year, time drifts along ♪
Xie Qingyuan.
♪ Warmth and chill
of mortal meet and part ♪
You've always prided yourself on
being able to see through people, right?
♪ No need to heed the wind's soft whisper
and ask about your return ♪
Why can't you tell
I have no ill intentions towards you?
♪ Wild geese soar through deep clouds,
waiting for the moon to rest ♪
We'll form an alliance
and share weal and woe.
Compared to East Pearls,
♪ Old memories lie heavy,
haunting every dream ♪
it seems you prefer jade.
I do have special feelings for you.
♪ Rises and falls take turns ♪
It depends on whether you agree or not.
♪ Phases of the moon,
unplanned to wax and wane ♪
♪ Count fallen blooms,
yet never count all pains of parting ♪
West of the city...
♪ You, tender yet sharp,
with thorns by your side ♪
Young Master Pei.
Take me to the west.
I have to find Lord Yan.
The west is dangerous.
Don't act rashly.
No!
♪ Like a dim yet blazing candle ♪
My family said I must find him.
I have to see him,
dead or alive.
I must see him!
♪ The wind and rain sigh,
the road stretches far ♪
If Lord Yan were here,
he wouldn't let you risk your life.
♪ Blossoms drift with streams,
affections softly stir ♪
-Back off!
-Let us out.
Please let us out.
Back off!
Move back!
Back!
You go first!
♪ You, tender yet sharp,
with thorns by your side ♪
♪ Like a dim yet blazing candle ♪
♪ The wind and rain sigh,
the road stretches far ♪
♪ Blossoms drift with streams,
affections softly stir ♪
♪ Half real, half illusion;
one cup of spring awakes me ♪
♪ Burned and released,
held by fate's hand ♪
♪ Greet the soft, mild evening breeze
and homebound sail to land ♪
♪ Slim moonbeams
weave tangled dreams all night ♪
♪ Lonely home boat glides slow
through dark twilight ♪
♪ I walk and gaze; one cup of spring
fades to lingering cheer ♪
Sure.
We have a deal.
When you return to Hengtang,
we'll still meet here.
With me around, don't be afraid,
Little Monkey.
Yan Rui!
Go!
Yan Rui is here!
After him!
Let's go.
I am Yan Rui.
If you have the guts,
come at me.
Don't touch her.
Come on!
Good.
What a man.
Attack!
♪ I counted every moment ♪
♪ Memories take root;
the annual rings grow ♪
♪ Who bore the parting wind ♪
♪ And wove it gently into the warmth
of the past? ♪
♪ I honor every scar upon your hand ♪
♪ Through endless nights,
a lone soul wanders this mortal world ♪
♪ Turning back, we embrace—
one fleeting moment of love and hate ♪
♪ As flowers fall beneath the dusk ♪
♪ Sorrowed by many a farewell,
comforted by sweet memories ♪
♪ One life, one love,
one heart devoted to you ♪
Lord Yan ordered me to come
to borrow troops from the Marquis.
Marquis.
You two share the same goal.
One person can't accomplish it alone.
If you work together,
you might just win.
It depends on whether you
are willing to take the gamble.
Kill!
Sister.
I found Healing Powder,
Bletilla Decoction,
and spirits.
Thank you.
Lord Yan is so badly injured,
can he still be cured?
Definitely.
I've studied medicine for so long
so that the people around me
won't leave me again.
I believe
Lord Yan
is blessed by heaven.
He will definitely recover.
Thank you.
I'll get back to work.